RG 103, Colt's Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company
Connecticut State Library
- Publications File, circa 1850-1980; T001481; 6.75 cubic feet
  - Advertising and Marketing Departments, circa 1850-1980
    - Foreign Materials/non-Colt's (Box 70)
      - M1892/instructions for use; Paris Minister of War, 1893 (Box 70)
      - M1892/instructions for use; Paris Minister of War, 1897 (Box 70)
      - Fabrique Nationale, 1899 (Box 70)
      - Fabrique Nationale, 1900 (Box 70)
      - Fabrique Nationale, 1906 (Box 70)
      - Revue d'armee Belgue, 1907 (Box 70)
      - Steyr-N. Pieper system/West Germany, 1909 (Box 70)
      - Frommer c.7.65 pistol/Budapest (with enclosures), 1910 (Box 70)
      - Royal/Cuba, 1911 (Box 70)
      - Martian/Cuba, 1911 (Box 70)
      - Star/Cuba, 1911 (Box 70)
      - Novelty/2-page pamphlet advertising N. Pieper pocket 6-shot revolver, 1911 July (Box 70)
      - Westley-Richards & Co. "Instanter", 1912 (Box 70)
        Received from Australia, 1912
      - Victoria/Cuba, 1913 (Box 70)
      - Swiss industrial Company/Vetterli breech-loading repeating military and sporting rifles, undated (Box 70)
      - Webley & Scott-handout, undated (Box 70)
      - Webley & Son-advertisement, undated (Box 70)
      - Bayard baby automatic pistol-Liege, undated (Box 70)
      - Abadie-Belgium, undated (Box 70)
      - Catalogue describing the Light Automatic Gun-Vicker's, Sons & Maxim, Ltd. (with photos and handwritten enclosure; Also, 1913 sketch by F.T. Moore), undated (Box 70)
    - Price Lists/non-Colt's (Box 70)
      - Liege manufactured firearms, 1852, 1886, 1890 (Box 70)
      - Melbourne, Australia, undated (Box 70)
      - Westley-richards prices, undated (Box 70)
    - Operation of firearms/Instructions for use (Box 70)
      Includes various circulars and handouts, such as an early 1850s page with "directions for loading and managing Colt's pistols" (from Beware of Counterfeits advertisement), and a typed sheet giving loading directions and taking apart revolvers.
      - Colt Manual on Target and Defense Shooting (Box 70)
      - How to Shoot (Box 70)
      - What Every Parent Should know... (Box 70)
      - Handgunning and Winning (Box 70)
      - The Handgun Manual (Box 70)
      - Shooting Suggestions (Box 70)
      - Special Instructions (Box 70)
      - Do all safety devices really safeguard? (Box 70)
      - More Fun with Your .22 Rifle (Box 70)
      - Handling the Handgun (2 different versions) (Box 70)
      - How to Organize and Conduct a Revolver Club (Box 70)
      - Instructions and Operation of Colt Automatic Machine Gun (MG 50) 1940 October Vol. II (4 copies) Vol. IIIa (2 copies) Vol. IIIa-1 (3 copies) Vol. IIIb (4 copies) Vol. IIIb-1 (3 copies) Vol. IVa (1 copy) Vol. IV (2 copies) (Box 70)
      - Instructions for Automatic Machine Guns and Rifles (MG 38/MG 38B) (4 copies) 1939 March (Box 70)
      - Browning Machine Gun Technical Manual 1942 April (Box 70)
      - Contractor's Operations Manual-Colt AR-15 (Box 70)
      - Technical Manual M-16 (2 copies) 1966 August (Box 70)
      - Technical Manual M-16 (2 copies) 1974 March (Box 70)
      - Elementary Instructions for Operations of Colt Automatic Gun M1914 Mod "R" (Box 70)
      - The Colt Cap and Ball Revolver (Haven and Belden 1940-reprint) (Box 70)
      - Description and Nomenclature of Colt Automatic Gun (Box 70)
      - Description of Colt Automatic Gun (2 copies) (Box 70)
    - Price lists (Box 70)
      - Retail, 1855-1972 (Box 70)
      - Wholesale, 1899-1980 (Box 70)
    - Proofs and Drafts (Box 70)
      Includes drawings, sketches, photos and first proofs of woodcuts of Colt's arms for use in catalogues, advertisements, and price lists. In-original folder, dated 1889.
      Some items are also dated individually.
      Also, proofs for Lightning Magazine Rifle (13 copies) and (5 copies) proofs for advertising copy (also see Advertising and Marketing/Lay-outs (oversize). Blueprints for special grip for 38c. pistol (No. 540,275-1933 April 4)
      Also, drafts of printed material:
      A Century of Achievement, A. L. Ulrich, 1937 (2 copies)
      Combat Shooting for Police, P. B. Weston, 1960 (copy)
      Crime Prevention, 1927-1931
      Makers of History, F. Romer, 1924-25
      Yankee Arms Maker, J. Rohan (uncorrected proofs)
    - Publisher's Advertising (book promotions) (Box 70)
      - The History of The Colt Revolver, Haven & Belden, 1937 (Box 70)
      - A Century of Achievement, A.L. Ulrich, 1937 (Box 70)
  - Printed Materials (Company-Related), 1851-1970
    Includes illustrations collected by the Colt Company of both Colt and non-Colt items, 1851-1964. Publications are also included,in this series. These are internally published: The Rampant Colt, 1929-1941, and The Coltsman, 1942-1944.
    Also contained in these files are stock certificates of the Colt Company. No dates (however, includes "Colt's Manufacturing Company"/1947). No index.
    - Illustrations/Colt's (Box 70)
      Also see Pinted Materials/Newspapers.
      - 1964 calendar with 1879 Colt's Ferry reproduction (Box 70)
      - L. Paeth's illustration of the history of the Colt Revolver (Box 70)
      - London Armory, 2 copies (Box 70)
      - "1851, Great Exibition" from the Illustrated London News, oversize (Box 70)
      - CT Exhibits at the International Exhibition, Paris, 1878; oversize (Box 70)
    - Illustrations/non-Colt's (Box 70)
      - Engraving of last steamer to run the Connecticut River above Hartford (C. Dexter), 1866 (Box 70)
      - The Old State House (Box 70)
      - Aetna Life Home Office (Box 70)
      - Comparigraph of arms period/wheellock, flintlock, matchlock (Box 70)
      - Cabin yacht "Mascot" with 'disc' type engine, 1881 (Box 70)
    - Publications/Internal (Colt Company publications) (Box 70)
      - The Rampant Colt, (Electrical Division) 1929 September-1941 September (Box 70)
      - The Coltsman, 1942 September-1944 March (Box 70)
    - Publications/External (Box 70)
      Articles written about the Colt Company and its product line.
      - Broadcasts/Lectures (Box 70)
        Arranged by date presented.
        - Royal United Service Institution, "Magazine Rifles & Repeaters", Lt. Col. G.V. Fosbery, 1883 June 23 (Box 70)
        - WDRC/Hartford radio 6:00-6:05 p.m.; "A Newcomer's Impression of Hartford", B. Rufe - Manager of Goodyear Service, 1934 November 15 (Box 70)
        - Address delivered at 17th Annual meeting of Army Ordnance Association - "Guaranties of Peace". (see Army Ordnance-articles), 1935 October (Box 70)
        - Talk delivered at Ogden Industrial Club meeting and broadcast over WKLO; "John Browning and his Achievements", G.L. Becker, 1937 March 29 (Box 70)
        - Address delivered at 13th Annual American Dinner of the Newcomer Society for the Study of the History of Engineering and Technology; "Interchangeable Manufacture", J.W. Roe of New York University, 1937 April 21 (Box 70)
        - WTIC/Hartford radio 7:45 p.m., on Colt's; The Spotlight, sponsored by The Hartford Electric Light Company, 1937 October 21 (Box 70)
        - WABC/New York radio 6:45-7:00 p.m.; "Guns and Gangsters", Honorable E. Celler & Honorable B. McMahon, 1937 December 11 (Box 70)
        - Great Lakes Regional Conference of the National Association of Real Estate Boards in Cincinatti, "Colt Village", Aubrey Maddock, 1939 March 20 (Box 70)
        - "Walker-Colt" Repeating pistol", Capt. J.E. Hicks, 1940 (Box 70)
        - TV program, "The Arm of Law and Order", with Al Marsters of Colt's, 1953 (Box 70)
        - "The Hawken Shop", C.L. Quick, undated (Box 70)
        - Lecture presented by G. Vander Haeghen, "The Automatic Pistol", (copy of the French translation), undated (Box 70)
      - Periodicals (Box 70A)
        Arranged alphabetically.
        - Africana Notes & News (Box 70A)
          - "The Introduction of the Revolver into South Africa", G. Tylden, 1953 September, p. 122. (Box 70A)
        - American Archivist, The (Box 70A)
          - "The Evaluation & Presentation of Business Archives", O.W. Holmes, vol. 1:14, 1938 October, p. 171. (Box 70A)
        - American Collector, The (Box 70A)
          - "The Metal Flask", G. Coopernail, 1937 November, p. 10. (Box 70A)
        - American Mercury, The (Box 70A)
          - "The First Munitions King", J. Rohan, 1936 March, p. 351. (Box 70A)
        - American Rifleman (Box 70A)
          - "Hand-Gun History", R. McHenry, 1923 August, p. 129. (Box 70A)
          - "Johnny Colt", R. McHenry, vol. LXXI, No. 6, 1938 October, p. 168. (part 2) (Box 70A)
          - "Some Spark Photographs, Recoil and Pressure Curves of the 45 Caliber Colt Automatic Pistol", P.P. Quayle, 1926 February. (Box 70A)
          - "The Old Colt Revolving Rifles", P. Jenkins, 1928 June. (photocopy) (Box 70A)
          - "Pistol Progress - 1871", Major J.S. Hatcher, 1931 May, p. 31. (Box 70A)
          - "Forgotten Guns of the Early 70's", P. Jenkins, 1931 May, p. 33. (Box 70A)
          - "The Invention of the Central-Fire Primer", Major J. Clark, 1931 May. (Box 70A)
          - "Colt's Arms in the '70's", A.L. Ulrich, 1931 May, p. 42. (Box 70A)
          - "What Made the Spark-Notes on the history of gun-locks", C. Haven, 1937 December, p. 4. (Box 70A)
          - "Federal Firearms Registration", C.B. Lister, 1938 January, 2 copies (Box 70A)
          - "Colt Service Model Ace", Lt. Col. J. S. Hatcher, 1938 January. (Box 70A)
          - "Henry Aston & His Pistols", L.D. Antwerp, 1942 January. (reprint) (Box 70A)
          - "Lightweight Colt Automatics", staff, 1949 September, p. 34. (Box 70A)
          - "Early Snub-Nosed Colt's", J. DuMont, 1956 August, p. 22. (Box 70A)
          - "Production & Purchases of Civil War Revolvers", J. Baentali, 1956 December. (Box 70A)
          - "Colt Mark III Passes Shooting Tests", staff, 1969 October, p. 70. (Box 70A)
        - Arms and the Man (Box 70A)
          - "The Paterson & the Walker Colts", December 1917, p. 205, 'sniper'. (Box 70A)
          - "The Peacemaker", S.J. Fort, 1922 February, p. 9. (Box 70A)
        - Army & Navy Journal (Box 70A)
          - "Colt's Automatic Pistol Adopted", 1911 April, p. 922, 3 copies (Box 70A)
        - Army Ordnance (Box 70A)
          - "Facts About 'Munitions Makers'", 1934 May-June, p. 361. (Box 70A)
          - "Organization for Defense", Brig. Gen. B. Crowell, 1935 November. (Box 70A)
          - "The Art of Victory", B. Baruch, 1935 November. (Box 70A)
          - "Peace, War and Munitions", N. Baker, 1935 November. (Box 70A)
          - "Origins of Our Modern Guns", Col. R. Birnie, 1935 November. (Box 70A)
          - "Our Lines of Defense", R.E. Flanders, 1935 November. (Box 70A)
          - "The Adams Revolver", S.B. Haw, 1938 January-February, p. 219. (Box 70A)
          - "The Machine Gun", Lt. Col. C. Goddard, 1942 May-December, 1943 January-February. (reprint) (Box 70A)
          - "Machine Guns of the United States, 1895-1944", Major B.R. Lewis, 1945 July-August, 1946 March-April. (Box 70A)
        - Art Journal (Box 70A)
          - "Homes of America-Armsmear", VII, 1876 November, p. 321. (Box 70A)
        - Bookbinding & Book Promotion (Box 70A)
          - "Bookvertising", Review of A Century of Achievement. (Box 70A)
        - Chamber's Edinburgh Journal (Box 70A)
          - "What is a Revolver?", W. & R. Chambers, 1853 December, p. 3. (Box 70A)
        - The Christian Century (Box 70A)
          - "Profits From Blood-How Long?", P. Hutchinson, 1937 May. (Box 70A)
        - Collector-Dealer (Box 70A)
          - "The Rim-Fire Peacemaker", 1957 July, p. 6. (Box 70A)
        - Collier's (Box 70A)
          - "Goose Killers", G. Creel, 1937 January, p. 26, 2 copies (Box 70A)
        - Collier's Weekly (Box 70A)
          - "How to Train Defense Workers", H.F. Pringle, 1941 January, p. 23. (Box 70A)
        - Connecticut Circle (Box 70A)
          - "What the Growth of Aviation Means to Connecticut", H.L. Williams, 1939 September, p. 6. (on Pratt & Whitney Co.) (Box 70A)
        - Connecticut Historical Society Bulletin (Box 70A)
          - "Colt-Walker Contract", J.E. Parsons, 1948 April, p. 9. (Box 70A)
        - Connecticut Industry, 1939 February. (Box 70A)
        - Copper & Brass Research Association Bulletin, 1937 December. (Box 70A)
        - Detective Fiction Weekly (Box 70A)
          - "A Mystery of the Tombs-murder conviction of John Colt", M. Abbott, 1930 February, p. 683. (Box 70A)
        - Dictionary of American History (Box 70A)
          - "The Colt Six-Shooter". (typed copy) (Box 70A)
        - DuPont Magazine, The (Box 70A)
          - "The Course of Empire", B. Darlington, vol. 96, No. 6-7, p. 168., 2 copies (Box 70A)
          - "Arms and Two Men-Remington and Rifles; Hartley and Cartridges", 1932 May, p. 5. (Box 70A)
        - Engineering (Box 70A)
          - "Clyde Shipbuilding and Marine Engineering, 1882", 1883 February. (extract) (Box 70A)
        - Factory Management & Maintenance (Box 70A)
          - "Industry and the Next War", L.C. Morrow, 1938 May, p. 46. (Box 70A)
        - Field & Stream (Box 70A)
          - "Makers of Famous Guns", E.O. Perrin, 1922 July, p. 289, 2 copies (Box 70A)
        - Financial Survey, The (Box 70A)
          - "Colt's Enters a New Epoch", E. Newmarker, 1929, p. 40. (Box 70A)
        - Fortune (Box 70A)
          - "Cadillac", 1938 December. (Box 70A)
          - "Company Collections", 1953 January, p. 94. (Box 70A)
        - Freehold (Box 70A)
          - "$6.66 per room per month", 1937 October, Real Estate News and Comments, (Colt Village). (Box 70A)
        - Gun & Cartridge Record (Box 70A)
          - "Who's Who...Charles Coles", J. Murphy, 1953 March, p. 1. (Box 70A)
          - "The Winchester Story", staff, 1953 March, p. 4. (Box 70A)
        - Gun Collecting (Box 70A)
          - "Paterson & Walker Colts", J. DuMont. (Box 70A)
        - Gun Report, The (Box 70A)
          - "Arms of the Russo-Turkish War", 1939. (Box 70A)
          - "Keep Your Powder Dry", F. Braucher, 1941 June, p. 1. (Box 70A)
          - "Facts About Flasks", J. Serven, 1941 July. (Box 70A)
          - "More Facts About Flasks", J. Serven, 1941 August. (Box 70A)
        - Guns (Box 70A)
          - "White House and Midwest Cops", 1962 February, p. 32. (Box 70A)
        - Guns and Ammo (Box 70A)
          - "The Living Legend that was Sam'l Colt", A. Chernoff, 1962 November. (Box 70A)
          - "Commemorative Guns", W. Beinfield, 1970 March. (reprint) (Box 70A)
        - Guns & Hunting (Box 70A)
          - "A Look at the Varmint-Handguns", 1963 July, p. 25. (Box 70A)
        - Harper's Monthly (Box 70A)
          - "Slaughter for Sale", J. Gunther, 1934 May, p. 649. (Box 70A)
        - Harper's New Monthly Magazine (Box 70A)
          - "Hole-in-the-Day", J. Micoley, 1862, p. 186. (Box 70A)
        - Harper's Weekly (Box 70A)
          - "Samuel Colt", 1902 April, p. 446. (Box 70A)
        - Heat Treating & Forging (Box 70A)
          - "Heating Processes in Small Arms Manufacture", F.M. Prendergast, 1940 October, p. 511. (Box 70A)
        - Hobbies (Box 70A)
          - "Unusual Colt Percussion Arms", J.E. Serven, 1935 April, p. 90. (Box 70A)
          - "Colt Powder Flasks", W.F.S. Quick, 1941 January, p. 100. (Box 70A)
          - "Rare American Powder Flasks", W.F.S. Quick, 1941 April, p. 101. (Box 70A)
        - Holiday (Box 70A)
          - "The Killer", circa 1954 August, p. 69. (Box 70A)
            Doc Holliday
        - Hoofs & Horns (Box 70A)
          - "The Elegant Era in America - Fancy Guns and Famous Actors", J. Serven, undated, p. 4. (Box 70A)
        - Hossthief Gazette, The, Miller Bedford, 1942 April. (Box 70A)
        - Household Words (Box 70A)
          A weekly journal.
          - "Revolvers", C. Dickens, 1854 June, p. 352. (copy) (Box 70A)
        - Illustrated Inventor, The (Box 70A)
          - "Terry's Patent Breech-Loading Rifles", No. 16, 1958 February. (Box 70A)
        - Illustrated London News, The (Box 70A)
          - "Guns & Rifles at British Sporting Exhibition", 1938 January. (Box 70A)
          - "The Gatling Battery Gun", 1867 March 23, p. 300. (Box 70A)
        - Imperial Journal of Arts, Sciences, Mechanics & Engineering, The, undated, p. 600. (photocopy) (Box 70A)
        - Importer's Guide, The (Box 70A)
          - "Industrial Use for the Colt Machine Gun", 1924 May, p. 77. (Box 70A)
        - Industrial Heating (Box 70A)
          - "Heat Treating Small Arms", 1940 August, p. 690. (Box 70A)
        - Investigator, The (Box 70A)
          - "Colt's Gun Collection", FBI Recreation Assoiciation, 1956 April. (Box 70A)
        - Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly (Box 70A)
          - "From Stone-Hammer to Breech-Loader", A. Trumble, vol. V, No. 2, 1878 February, p. 129. (Box 70A)
        - Leslie's Weekly (Box 70A)
          - "T. Roosevelt's Rough Riders", 1898 June, p. 396. (Box 70A)
            Photograph
        - Life (Box 70A)
          - "U.S. is Weak in Arms and Industry is Unprepared", 1938 December, p. 45. (Box 70A)
          - "The Color Spectacle-Colt's Pistols", E. Elisofon, 1962 March, p. 48. (Box 70A)
        - Lubrication & Civilization/Esso Oil-Ways (Box 70A)
          - "New England Craftsmanship", 1935 July. (Box 70A)
        - Metropolitan Hartford (Box 70A)
          - "Colt's Aids Business & Sport", G.B. Armstead, 1935 September. (Box 70A)
        - Month at Goodspeed's (Box 70A)
          - "Gatlin and His Colt", 1939 October, p. 14., 2 copies. (Box 70A)
        - Newsweek (Box 70A)
          - "Report on National Defense", - special issue, 1940-1941. (Box 70A)
        - Oil-Power/Standard Oil Company (Box 70A)
          - "Big Guns", 1931 April, p. 36. (Box 70A)
        - Outdoor Life (Box 70A)
          - "A Home Museum of Famous Guns", 1935 May. (about A. Foster, Jr.) (Box 70A)
          - "Colt's - The Side-Arm that Built a Nation, 1836-1935", undated. (Box 70A)
        - Outlook, The (Box 70A)
          - "The Pistol - The Development of the American Revolver", 1919 June, p. 259. (Box 70A)
        - Pawnee Bill's Pony Club Newsletter (Box 70A)
          - "Life Story of Pawnee Bill", p. 3. (Box 70A)
        - Reserve Officer, The (U.S. Army) (Box 70A)
          - "Automatic Pistol Marksmanship", Capt. R.C. Springer, 1939 September, p. 7. (Box 70A)
          - "New Weapons Adopted", 1938 December. (37mm antitank & antiaircraft guns) (Box 70A)
        - Romance of a Firearms Collector (Box 70A)
          - "The 13th Texas Colt", C.W. Sawyer, undated, p. 280. (Box 70A)
        - Saga of the Sixshooter (Box 70A)
          - C.E. Freeman, Ch. II-V, p. 129. (Box 70A)
        - Saturday Evening Post (Box 70A)
          - "The Pink Slip Strike", R. Pitcairn, 1935 June, (reprint). (Box 70A)
          - "We Can Defend America", Gen. J. Hagood, 1936 November, p. 20. (Box 70A)
        - Scribner's (Box 70A)
          - "The Rifle that Won the Revolution", R. Burlingame, 1938 February. (Box 70A)
        - Shooter's Corner, The (Box 70A)
          - "Colt's Metallic-Cartridge Long Guns", P. Kuhlhoff, p. 141. (Box 70A)
          - "More About the Spencer", P. Kuhlhoff, p. 169. (Box 70A)
        - Southern Sportsman, The (Box 70A)
          - "America's Munitions", B. Crowell, 1941 May, p. 47. (Box 70A)
        - Sporting Goods Dealer, The (Box 70A)
          - "Man Behind Browning", 1955 February. (on son Val) (Box 70A)
          - "At Colt's with Capt. E.C. Crossman", 1919 December, p. 31, 2 copies. (Box 70A)
        - Sporting Goods Journal (Box 70A)
          - "You Cannot Control That Way", Capt. E.C. Crossman, 1934 December, p. 21. (Box 70A)
        - Sports Afield (Box 70A)
          - "Too Good to Leave in the Past", 1961 October, p. 41, 4 copies. (Box 70A)
        - Time - Book Review (Box 70A)
          - "Those Were the Days", E. Hewitt. (about Cooper & Hewitt families, mentions Maxim and his inventions) (Box 70A)
          - Letters - "Americana", p. 5. (Box 70A)
        - Today (Box 70A)
          - "Behind the Battlefield", 1936 December, p. 9. (Box 70A)
        - Touring Topic (Box 70A)
          - "Six Shots Rang Out!", C.N. Hess, 1929 March, p. 20. (Box 70A)
        - United States Magazine (Box 70A)
          - "Repeating Fire-Arms: A Day at the Armory of Colt's Patent Fire-arms Manufacturing Company", Vol. IV, No. 3, 1857 March, p. 221. (Box 70A)
        - Waffe & Sport (Weapon & Sport) (Box 70A)
          - "General Remarks on the History of Weapons", 1926 October, p. 12. (Box 70A)
        - Western Horseman, The (Box 70A)
          - "Federal Cavalryman - The Civil War Soldier", R. Steffen, 1962 January, p. 38. (Box 70A)
        - Western New England Magazine (Box 70A)
          - "Industries of Western New England - Firearms", J.M. Freeman, 1913 March, p. 119. (Box 70A)
        - Western Writers of America (Box 70A)
          - "The Roundup", Vol. VIII, No. 38 1960 August, p. 6. (Box 70A)
          - "Westerns Triggered Big Boom for Colt", 1960 August. (SAA production resumed) (Box 70A)
        - Wiring for Profit (Box 70A)
          - "The story of Colt's", J. Savage, July (no year), 2 copies (Box 70A)
        - "Making Them Smoke", B.K. Wingate, p. 24. (Box 70A)
        - "Gleanings from the US Ordnance Report - Testing the Colt Automatic Pistol", undated. (Box 70A)
        - "Are They Putting J. Edgar Hoover on the Spot?", W. Irwin. (Box 70A)
        - "The Beginnings of Winchester", Ch. I, p. 1. (Box 70A)
        - "Winchester Manufacturing Methods and Standards", Ch. II, p. 8. (Box 70A)
        - "Mr. Gatling's Coffee Grinder", F.J. Gillespie, undated, p. 32. (Box 70A)
      - Newspaper articles
        Arranged chronologically by date of newspaper.
        - Ballou's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion, "Sketches of Eminent Persons - Samuel Colt", 1852, p. 80. (Box 70B)
        - Gleason's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion, "Crystal Palace Exhibition", 1853 November, p. 320., copy (Box 70B)
        - Supplement to the Courant, "Colt in the Caucasus", 1854 May 6, p. 69. (Box 70B)
        - The (London) Daily News, "The New Fashioned Fire Arms", 1854 July 18, photostat. (Box 70B)
        - Gleason's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion, "Tales of Revolvers", 1854 September 23, p. 179. (Box 70B)
        - Supplement to the Courant, "Colonel Colt's Pistols", 1856 June 21, p. 116. (Box 70B)
        - Harper's Weekly, "Illustrations & Story - Colt's Fire", 1864 February 2, pp. 125-126. (Box 70B)
        - Harper's Weekly, "Illustrations of Colt's Armory Fire", 1864 February 27, p. 132. (Box 70B)
        - Scientific American, "Conflagration at Colt's Armory", 1864 February 20, March 12, p. 117., typed copies (Box 70B)
        - The Turf, Field & Farm, "The Gun Trade in America", with advertisements for B. Kittredge & Co., Colt's agents 1875 March 19. (Box 70B)
        - The Daily Graphic, "American Arms in Europe", 1877 April 20, p. 353. (Box 70B)
        - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, "The Evolution of the Bicycle", p. 157, also "Army Rifle Competitions" - illustrations, 1889 October 5. (Box 70B)
        - New York Daily Tribune, "Novel Coast Defense - Berdan's Gunboat", 1892. (Box 70B)
        - Hartford Sunday Post, "Colt's Armory, the Home of the Best Revolver in the World", 1911 October 22. (Box 70B)
        - New York American, "How to Shoot", Alfred Lane, 1914 March 22. (Box 70B)
        - Sunday Globe Magazine, "8 Million Shots Ready for the Huns", 1918 June, p. 12. (Box 70B)
        - Hartford Courant, "Government Honors Colt Co.", 1920 March 13, front page. (Box 70B)
        - New Haven Register, "Old Timers Melange of Subjects - New and Old", 1922 March 12, p. 7. (Box 70B)
        - Macon (Missouri) Daily Chronicle, "The Colt's in History", 1930. (Box 70B)
        - The Branford Review, "The Story of Small Arms", R.A. Lull, 1932 September 8. (Box 70B)